Hey, Ash.
Where are we?
Well, we just crossed
the Tennessee border.
- Which would put us...
- Yeah?
Which would put us...
Right...
...Here!
Turn!
What the hell was that?
Are you trying to kill us?
Don't blame me!
It's your steering wheel!
Damn thing jerked right
out of my hands.
I don't understand it.
I had this thing in for
a tune-up yesterday
and they said they'd
go over everything.
Well you better take it back
because the damn thing don't work.
The one thing that does
work is this lousy horn.
Go to hell!
I'm not honking at you!
Jesus Christ!
Hey Scotty!
What's this place like anyway?
Well, the guy that's renting
it says it's an old place.
Little run down, but it's
right up in the mountains.
Yeah, and the best part is
that we get it so cheap.
Why are we getting
it so cheap?
Well, I don't know.
Might be in real bad shape.
You mean, nobody's
seen this place yet?
Well, not yet.
Well, it might not
be that bad.
- No.
- Actually, it might be kind of nice.
- Yeah.
- It's probably a real pit!
I think this is where we get off.
This is the bridge we're
going to cross?
Jesus Christ! The whole thing's
falling apart on us!
Don't let the noise fool you girls,
this thing's solid as a rock.
It's supposed to be one
of these on here.
Join Us!
Dead bodies in the cellar.
Will you stop it?
I would very much like to make
a toast for all this evening.
Ah, as a Greek friend
of mine once said...
He said...
I...
Ok, Ok, Ok...
Nis, nis...
...Tu, Tu, Tu...
Tu, Ta, Rim.
Which means?
Party down!
Yeah!
What is this?
Whatever it is,
it's still down there.
I don't like cellars.
Let's just close it up.
It's probably just some animal.
An animal?
That is the stupidest
thing I ever heard of.
Jesus Christ!
There's something down there.
Maybe it is just some animal.
Yeah, you're probably right.
Probably just some animal.
Cheryl, why don't you go down
and check, make sure?
Scotty! I'm not going
down there!
Ok, Ok you cowards.
I'll go.
Be careful.
Back in a minute.
Hey Scotty!
You find anything?
Scotty!
Scotty?!
Scott!
He's just kidding around...
- Isn't he?
- Scotty!!
Scott!
Linda, get me a flashlight.
That's the only one
we brought up.
Then get the lantern.
Scotty?!
Boo!!
Hey! Come here, I wanna
show you something.
Look at all this stuff.
I bet this still shoots.
Probably does.
Oh!...God!
Oh God!
Look at this!
This kind of looks like
your old girlfriend.
Come on. Let's take this
stuff upstairs.
I'll grab the recorder...
...and you get everything
else now.
This guy was a real turd...
everybody hated him...
Like...Like you, kind of.
Yeah, just like me.
I'm gonna break your face.
...also invented this western stuff.
He makes all this little models...
Ok, shush!
Listen to this...
This is the tape I
found downstairs.
It has been a number of years
since I began excavating
the ruins of Candar with
a group of my colleges.
Now, my wife and I have
retreated to a small
cabin in the solitude
of these mountains.
Here I continued my research
undisturbed by the myriad
...distractions of
modern civilization
and far from the
groves of academe.
I believe I have
made a significant
find in the Candarian Ruins.
A Volume of Ancient
Sumarian burial
practices and funerary
incantations.
It is entitled
"Naturon Demonto"
...roughly translated,
"Book of the Dead".
The book is bound
in human flesh...
...and inked in human blood.
It deals with demons and demon
resurrection and those forces
...which roam the forest and
dark bowers of man's domain.
The first few pages
warn that these
enduring creatures may lie...
...dormant but are
never truly dead.
They may be recalled
to active life
...through the incantations
presented in this book.
It is through recitation
of these passages...
...that the demons are given
license to possess the living.
What did you do that for?
It was just getting good!
I just don't want to hear
it anymore, that's all.
Scotty, c'mon.
Leave her alone, man.
Hey, come on...
I just want to hear
the rest of it.
No big deal.
Tatre-ah-mis-trobeen
-ha-zar-ta
Tantir-man-ov-mansiz-
onn-hazann-sobar.
Sum-unda-rop-sa Dar-his-
hyk-err-duns-de-rod-sa
Kanda!
Shut it off!
Shut it off!!
Kanda!
Shut it off!!!
Oh my God!
Cheryl! Where're you going?
I can't believe this!
Scott, you knew not
to play that!
I mean c'mon, you knew
it was upsetting her.
You just don't know when you're
taking something too far.
Don't give me that!
You were playing it too.
You could've shut it off.
I mean... big deal!
She's nuts!
I mean it's just a joke, c'mon!
Jesus Christ.
She acts like she's
three years old or something.
Listen. Why don't we stay up for
a while and listen to the storm?
All right, yeah.
Let me check on Cheryl first
to see if she's Ok.
Stealing from the blind, eh?
It's for you.
Ash, how sweet of you.
- Would you put it on?
- Oh, Sure.
I was going to give it to you
before we came up here, but...
...things got so
hectic, this is really
the first chance we've
had to be alone.
Take a look.
Oh, Ash! It's beautiful!
I really love it.
I'll never take it off.
Join Us!
Is anybody out there?
I know someone's out there!
I heard you.
I heard you in the cellar.
Join Us!
Ashley!
Help!
What the hell happened to you?
Cheryl, what's the matter
with you?
Did something in the woods
do this to you?
No! It was the woods themselves!
They're alive Ashley!
The trees!
They're alive!
Ash. Why don't I take her in the
back room so she can lie down...
I'm not lying down!
I want to get out of here.
I want to leave this
place right now.
Right now, Ashley!
Wait a minute!
I sure as hell am not leaving
any place tonight.
- Cheryl.
Cheryl, there's nothing
out there.
Trees do not attack people.
Ashley! Will you drive
me into town or not?
Right now?!
Look, sure, sure, I'll
take you into town,
but just listen to
what you're saying.
I don't care how it sounds.
I wanna get out of this
place right now!
Ok, maybe you could stay
somewhere in town tonight.
I know it's not gonna start.
It's not gonna let us leave.
Why are you stopping?
Wait here a minute.
Do you see something?
Where're you going?
Ashley!
It's not going to let us go!
I told you! I told you!
Why won't you listen to me?
I know now that
my wife has
become host to a
Candarian demon.
I fear that the
only way to
stop those possessed
by the...
...spirits of the
book is through
the act of...bodily
dismemberment.
I believe now to avoid
this horror, but for
myself, I have seen the
dark shadows moving...
...in the woods and I have no
doubt that whatever I have
resurrected through
this book is
sure to come
calling...for me.
Ok, ah, let me think.  Ummm...
It's a seven?
Oh! What suit?
Ahh... diamonds. No wait!
Ummm, hearts!
Oh My! It's seven of hearts!
You're right!
Hey Ash! I guessed
the card right!
Yeah... truly amazing, Linda.
I don't know, but I
think it's really
some sort of extra
sense or something...
- ...you know, like ESP.
- Ok, try this one...
Ok... It's a seven.
- I don't believe it!
- ...of Spades.
Queen of Spades.
Four of Hearts.
Eight of Spades.
Two of Spades.
Jack of Diamonds.
Jack of Clubs!
Why have you disturbed
our sleep?
Awakened us...
...from our ancient slumber?
You will die! Like the
others before you.
One by one we will take you.
What happened to her?
Did you see her eyes?
Oh Ash, I'm scared.
What's wrong with her?
Cheryl! Stop it!
- Oh, Shit!
- Join Us! Join...
Ash. I think we ought to
get out of here.
Yeah.
We still have a few more
hours before morning.
I don't think I can
wait that long.
You have to.
We all have to!
And then in the morning,
we'll get in the car...
and we'll take the bridge.
And...
Why does she keep making
those horrible noises?!
I don't know!
And what about her eyes?
What about her eyes?
For God's Sake, What h
appened to her eyes?!
Everything's going to
be all right.
Scotty. I think there's
something out there.
Go to bed, and get
some sleep. Ok?
Shelly?
Thank you, I don't
know what I would have
done if I had remained
on those hot coals...
...burning my pretty flesh.
You have pretty skin.
Give it to us!
Join Us!
Hit her!
Hit it!
Scott?
Yeah?
What is...
What are we going to do?
We're going to bury her.
You...can't bury Shelly.
She's a... she's a friend of
ours, isn't she?
Ash, she's dead.
Shelly's dead.
We gotta bury her now.
Linda's still sleeping.
I think once her leg...
I'm getting out of here.
Scott, we can't take Linda
anywhere with a leg like that.
We don't even know
if there is any
other way back
besides the bridge.
Well, maybe there's a
hiking trail, or an old
road or some other way
around the cliff.
I mean there's gotta be another
way besides the bridge.
Listen to me.
Linda cannot walk
with a leg like that.
She can't even stand up.
Well, then we'll
leave her here.
Until we can send
somebody back.
What are you, crazy?
Look! I'm getting out!
I don't care what
happens to her.
She's your girlfriend,
you take care of her.
I'm getting the hell out of here.
Right now!
Soon all of you will be like me.
And then who will lock you
up in the cellar?
Ash! Ash!
- Oh my God!
- Help me!
Help me, Ash.
Scotty. You're going to be Ok.
You're going to be just fine.
You'll see.
Ash. It's not going to
let us leave.
Cheryl...Cheryl was right.
We're all going to die here!
No, we're not going to die.
We're all going to die.
All of us!
No, we're not going to die!
We're not going to die!
We're gonna get out of here.
Now listen to me, Scotty.
Is there a way around
the bridge?
Scotty!
Listen to me, please.
For God's sake!
Scott!
Ash...Ash, I don't wanna die.
You're not going to leave
me are you, Ash? Are you?
I don't wanna die.
You're not going to leave
me here are you?
Are you, Ash?
Scotty! Now c'mon listen
to me for God's sake!
Is there a way around
the bridge?
There's a way. The trail.
But the trees, Ash.
They know.
Don't you see, Ash?
They're alive!
Shut up!
Shut up, Linda.
Kill her!
Kill her if you can,
loverboy.
God! Forgive me, Linda.
Oh, Ash. Help me, please!
Ash.
Help me, please...Ash.
Oh, Ash. Please, don't let
them take me away again.
- Please.
- No, I won't. I won't. I promise.
Ashley. Ashley, help me.
Let me out of here.
Ashley? Ash, help me.
I'm... I'm all right now.
I'm all right now, Ashley...
I'm all right.
Unlock this chain and
let me out.
Cheryl?
I'm all right now,
Ashley!
Come unlock the chain
and let me out!
I'm all right now.
It's your sister Cheryl.
You bastards!
Why are you torturing
me like this? Why?!
Shut up!
We're going to get you.
Not another peep.
Time to go to sleep.
We're...
It's Useless!
Useless!
In time, it will come for him
and then it will come for you!
Here. Here.
Now, the sun will be
up in an hour or so
and we can all get out
of here together.
You, me, Linda, Shelly.
Hmm...Well...Shelly...she...
We'll all be going
home together.
Wouldn't you like to
be going home?
I bet you'd like that,
wouldn't you?
Scott?
Join Us!
Oh, Linda.
Come to me.
The door.
The back door.
Shells. Where did I see t
hat box of shells?
We're gonna get you!
Shut up, Linda.
- We're all gonna die.
- Shut up.
- All of us.
- Shut up!
How sweet of you....God!
Forgive me, Linda.
...is through the act of...
bodily dismemberment.
Hit her. Hit her.
Hit it!
Oh, Come on. Come on.
Why are you torturing
me like this?
Linda.
Join Us!
Oh! No, God!